MOHAMED HAMMAM

E-mail: mohamedhammam439@gmail.com Website: https://github.com/mohamedhammam439@gmail.com

Phone: +201007903482 Address: Cairo, Egypt

Objective

Front End Developer with 1 year of experience in blending the art of design with the skill of programming to deliver an immersive and engaging user experience through efficient website development, proactive feature optimization, and relentless debugging.

Work experience

Back and Front

Feb 2021 — Present

Front-End Developer

- Delivered responsive, cross-browser compatible, and accessibility compliant websites, achieving 30% faster load time than the industry average
- Ensure efficient web development by supporting designers and app developers while resolving website performance issues
- Designed dynamic and browser compatible pages using React and React Native
- Design dynamic and browser compatible pages in react native in JSON file and render by dynamic components

Wathefa.Com

Jul 2020 — Feb 2021

Frontend Developer

- Delivered responsive, cross-browser compatible, and accessibility compliant websites, achieving 19% faster load time than the industry average
- Ensure efficient web development by supporting designers and app developers while resolving website performance issues
- Designed dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and Javascript.

Linked Forest

Jul 2020 — Nov 2020

Frontend Developer

- Designed dynamic and browser compatible pages using ReactJs, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and Javascript.
- Expand features, refine code, and improve processes, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement
- Built single-page applications (SPA), responsive web design, UI using HTML5 grid layouts, CSS3 media queries where it's an expression and can be used to either true or false.

Martians

Jan 2020 — Jul 2020

Frontend Developer

- Produced stunning visual elements of web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code while producing high quality, reusable markup using HTML5 and CSS3
- Designing frontend within object-oriented Javascript frameworks like ReactJs.

MOHAMED HAMMAM

Technical Skills

- HTML, CSS, Sass
- JavaScript, jQuery
- Front End frameworks (Reactjs with Redux and Hooks)
- React Native
- Responsive UI Design
- Visual Studio
- Github, Azure Devops Source Control

Education

Bachelor of Civil Engineering

2012 - 2017

Ain Shams University

Web Development Diploma

2020

Mesmak Academy

Projects

UNIEL WEBSITE & E-CONTENT WEBSITE

• using html , CSS , JS, JQuery , Bootstrap and Responsive Design

TODO LIST & CRUD & WEATHER APPS & MOVIE APP & SUPPORT 305

· using React js , Css , Bootstrap

TEFLY PROJECT & MARTIANS WEBSITE

• using html , Css , Bootstrap 4 , jQuery and Responsive Design

Wathefa.Com

• using html, Css, Bootstrap 4, jQuery and Responsive Design

Dress Shop & Electronic Shop

• using React, Material UI and Redux

References

Available Upon Request

MOHAMED HAMMAM 2